我们将介绍一个称为分辨率运动控制的重要概念。听起来
We're going to introduce an important concept called resolved rate motion control. It sounds
很复杂，但它真的很容易理解。对于很多现实世界的问题，我们可能会
complex but its really quite simple to understand. For a lot of real world problems, we might
感兴趣的是机器人末端执行器在笛卡尔空间中沿直线移动。
be interested in the robot end effector moving along a straight line in Cartesian space.
现在我们知道，如果我们移动，例如，关节角度1，我们移动关节角度2，然后
Now we know that if we move, for instance, joint angle 1, we move joint angle 2, then
机器人的末端往往在空间中以弧形移动。我们不希望它在弧形中移动。
the end of the robot tends to move in arcs in space. We don't want it to move in arcs.
我们希望它沿直线移动。所以我们开始指定笛卡尔速度
We want it to move along a straight a line. So we began to specify the Cartesian velocity
我们希望末端效应器跟随。我们想将其转换为所需的关节速度。
that we want the end effector to follow. We want to convert that then to the required joint velocity.
我们已经触及过这一点。我们采用所需的速度nu，我们乘以逆
We already touched on this. We take the desired velocity nu, we multiply it by the inverse
雅可比人，我们得到了我们需要的联合速度。我们计算逆Jacobian，
Jacobian and we get the joint velocity that we need. We compute that inverse Jacobian,
我们可以像在这里一样象征性地写出来。现在我需要做的就是拥有
we can write it out symbolically as I had done here. Now what I need to do is have the
机器人的硬件以所需的速度移动关节。但在机器人移动之后
robot's hardware move the joints at this desired velocity. But after the robot's been moving
在短时间内，关节角度矢量Q将改变为雅可比
for a short period, the joint angle vector Q will have changed so that that Jacobian
我计算过的将不再合适。所以我需要做的是定期
that I've computed will no longer be appropriate. So what I need to do then is periodically
更新雅可比矩阵。当我计算所需的机器人速度矢量时使用它
update the Jacobian matrix. And use that when I'm computing the desired robot velocity vector
Q点。所以这是移动机器人关节，更新雅可比，计算机器人的问题
Qdot. So it's a matter of moving the robot joints, updating the Jacobian, computing the
机器人关节速度，移动关节，更新雅可比等。无限期地重复这个。
robot joint velocity, moving the joints, updating the Jacobian and so on. Repeat this indefinitely.
大多数在数​​字计算机上运行的控制算法通常是离散时间算法。
Most control algorithms that run on a digital computer a typically discrete time algorithms.
那就是他们以离散的时间间隔计算东西。所以我们有一个时间表和
That is they compute things at discrete time intervals. So here we have a time line and
我们指出了一些时间步骤。时间1，时间2，时间3等。持续时间
we indicated a number of time steps. Time 1, time 2, time 3 and so on . The duration
在这些时间步骤中，我将用符号deltaT表示。它可能是1/10
of these time steps, I’m going to denote by the symbol delta T. It might be 1/10 of
一秒钟它可能是千分之一秒。这样的事情。每时每步都是什么
a second it might be a thousandth of a second. Something like that. At every time step what
我要做的是取出关节角度的当前值并称之为QK。那
I'm going to do is to take the current value of the joint angles and call that QK. That
代表K时的关节角度。
stands for joint angles at the time K.
要计算雅可比行列式，请采用逆，乘以我想要的速度
To compute the Jacobian, take the inverse, multiply it by the velocity that I want to
实现并计算在这个特定时间步骤我需要实现的Qdot。什么
achieve and compute the Qdot that I need to achieve at this particular time step. What
我要做的是采取联合速度Qdot我将它乘以deltaT所以
I'm going to do is take that joint velocity Qdot I'm going to multiply it by delta T so
这将给我一个关节角位移;这就是我想要关节多少
that will give me a joint angle displacement; that is how much I would want the joints to
移动到即将到来的时间间隔。
move over the coming time interval.
我将其添加到关节角度QK的当前值。这给了我机器人的机会
I add that to the current value of the joint angles QK. And that gives me the robot’s
目标。这就是我希望机器人关节角度在时间K+1的地方。然后我告诉了
target. That's where I want the robot joint angles to be at time K +1. Then I tell the
机器人硬件随着时间的推移将关节移动到这个新的关节角度配置
robot hardware to move the joints to this new joint angle configuration over the time
间隔deltaT.然后我会在必要时重复这些步骤。
interval delta T. And then I'll repeat this steps for as long as necessary.